-别问 -别说
- Don't ask. - Don't tell.
反正或许也挺明显的
It's probably obvious, anyway.
我哭了一夜
I was up all night crying.
看看她在不在家 歌洛莉亚
Let's see if she's here. Gloria?!
莎拉·芬克 我的实验室伙伴
Sarah Fink, my lab partner
我原希望有一天能成为我的爱情伴侣
who I hoped one day would be my love partner.
我发现某个我所谓的朋友在勾搭她
I caught one of my so-called friends hitting on her,
现在她就跟我们以前
and now she's like the fetal pig
一起做实验用的小猪一样
we once so happily shared --
冰凉 冷漠 无心
Cold, unresponsive, heartless.
你现在有两个选择
You got two choices --
你可以爬到楼上 沉浸在伤心浴缸中
You can mope your way up those stairs and soak in a pity bath,
也可以提起精神 昂首挺胸去学校
or you can pick yourself up, march into that school,
假装你根本不认识那姑娘
and act like you don't even know that girl.
谢谢
Thanks.
如果老妈问 就说我借了她的浴缸枕
If mom asks, I borrowed her tub pillow.
杰 别忘了一会儿把乔载去米奇和小卡家
Jay, don't forget to drop Joe at Mitch and Cam's later.
好 他们要我几点去...
Yeah, what time are they expecting me to, uh --
什么情况
Oh, what the hell?
是不是很萌啊
Oh, isn't it cute?
昨晚我去做美甲的时候
Last night when I went to do my nails,
那里的小姑娘给他做着玩的
the girls did it just for fun.
-造成一辈子的性别困惑有什么好玩的 -拜托
- What's fun about a lifetime of gender confusion? - Ay, please.
这不就跟你带他去看道奇队的比赛
It's the same as when you took him to the Dodgers game
回来还戴上了道奇队的帽子一样嘛
and you brought him back with that Dodgers cap.
你觉得呢 当然是大大不一样了
You think? Or is it different in every conceivable respect?
别忘了菲尔还在米奇和小卡家
Ay, and don't forget that Phil is gonna be meeting you
等着帮你
at Mitch and Cam's
把莉莉的公主城堡搬来这里呢
to help you bring Lily's princess castle here.
莉莉已经不玩那个了 但乔喜欢得很呢
She's outgrown it, but Joe loves that thing.
别做那种表情
Ay, don't make that face.
-你会搬回来的吧 -当然了 亲爱的
- You're gonna bring it, right? - Sure, honey.
好了 扶着他
Okay. Hold him.
薰衣草浴盐用完了 可真会挑时候
I picked a fine time to run out of lavender bath beads.
我原本想要两个猛男儿子
I wanted two rough and tumble boys.
结果我有了曼尼[修手指甲]
I got a Manny...
和帕蒂姑娘[修脚趾甲]
and a Pedi.
她是我第一个女朋友 真的
She's my first girlfriend, really.
明天这个时候 她就会在我们的客厅里
This time tomorrow, she'll be in our living room,
如果能顺利通过门廊的话
if we can fit her through the doorway.
行了 我忍不住要问一问了
Okay, I feel like I have to ask.
老爸想买个吃豆小姐游戏机
Dad's about to buy a "Miss pac-man."
是女士 刚刚纠正你多久了
Ms. What was our struggle for?
不是普通的吃豆女士游戏机
And not just any "Ms. Pac-man,"
而是1982年原装修复的矮款
but an original 1982 fully reconditioned podium-style unit.
带有原始的退币口
With original coin return.
他们还送了凳子呢
They're even throwing in the stool.
拜托
Come on!
好吧 你是对的 是挺傻的
Oh, you know, you're right. It's stupid.
那会占据实用东西的空间
Just be taking up space we need
比如那架钢琴 等等 是吗
for things we actually use, like the piano -- oh, wait.
你怎么回事
What's going on with you?
我头疼得厉害
Oh, I have a throbbing headache.
搞得我很难去
It's making it hard to...
装病吗
Pretend that you're sick?
是啊 你刚刚才吃了一大碗麦片
Yeah, you just ate a bushel of cereal.
检查一下奖牌盒有没有坏 小表砸们
Check the structural integrity of the trophy case, bitches,
因为老娘又要带点家伙什回来了
'cause mama's bringing home some hardware!
今天是学校颁奖日
Awards day at school --
一年中只有这天艾丽克斯会趾高气昂地走路
The one day of the year Alex has some real swagger.
讽刺的是 她非常不擅长这个
Ironically, the one thing she's not good at.
我说奖牌 你说奖牌
When I say "Trophy," You say "Trophy"!
奖牌
Trophy!
能给我点那什么吗
Can I get a wha-what?
什么
What?
我一直担心艾丽克斯拿了那么多奖
I always worried that Alex winning all those awards
会刺激到卢克 结果好像真的刺激到了
would bother Luke, and looks like it finally did.
在一个超级明星姐姐的阴影下长大 实属不易
Can't be easy growing up in the shadow of a superstar sister.
看看米奇尔就知道了
Look at Mitchell.
你有皇后吗
Okay, do you have any queens?
有啊 两个呢
Yeah, two big ones.
好了 你知道吗 第一次这么说是很搞笑
Okay, you know what? It was funny the first time.
现在就显得很刻薄了
Now it's just getting mean.
怎么回事
What was that?
波拉斯基先生 我们楼上的邻居 上周去世了
Mr. Polasky, our upstairs neighbor, died last week.
他93岁了 而且生病有段日子了
He was 93, and he'd been sick for a while.
所以 我们...我们想让他开心点
Yeah, and we -- we tried cheering him up
就在前庭挂了个"好起来"的标语
with a "Get well" sign in the front yard.
好了 看起来怎么样
Okay, how's that look?
很不错
Looks great.
说真的
Honestly.
不 不
Oh. No! No.
"好起来 孩子"
"Get well son"?
好了 算了
Okay, well, you know what?
反正"快点"显得有点专横
"Soon" seemed a little bossy anyway.
米奇和我一直在商量
Mitchell and I have always discussed
如果斯坦有什么不测
trying to buy the place
我们就把他的房子买下来
in the event something happened to Stan.
我们可以用多出来的空间改造成客房
We -- we could use the extra space for a guest room
或者办公室 甚至是
or an office or maybe even...
育婴室
a nursery.
我想再养个孩子
I think I may want another child.
但我不想告诉米奇尔
But I don't want to bring it up to Mitchell
给他造成压力
and put pressure on him
因为他一直很坚定地表示不想再养了
because he's been so adamant about not wanting one.
他最不想要的就是...
The last thing he's thinking about is a...
育婴室
Nursery.
最近我情绪有点不稳定
Lately, I've been having stirrings,
但因为过去就像是一辆可怕的情绪过山车
but because it was such an emotional roller coaster in the past,
我不想再经历一遍
I don't want to bring it up
除非我得到了某种启示...
unless I have some sort of indication...
我们意见一致
That we're both on the same page.
所以当歌洛莉亚问我们能否照看乔时
That's why, when Gloria asked if we'd watch Joe,
我说 当然啦
I said "Sure."
那或许可以提醒米奇尔
It'd be a chance to remind Mitchell
拥有宝宝的感觉有多好
how nice it is to...have a baby.
克莱尔·邓菲
Claire Dunphy.
有什么能帮你做的
What can I do you for?
你可帮我"做"不了什么
Oh, it's not so much what you can do me for.
听起来有点淫荡
Sounded a -- a tiny bit prostitute-y.
抱歉
I'm sorry about that.
实际上 我的确要请你帮个小忙
Actually, I do have a tiny favor to ask.
我爱你的家人
You know, I love your family.
-海莉是我们的返校节女王 -好吧
- I mean, Haley, our homecoming queen. - Yeah.
现在艾丽克斯赢得了每个学术奖项
And now Alex winning just about every academic award.
-我懂的 -教邓菲家的孩子是我的荣幸
- I know. - It's been an honor to teach the dunphy children.
我是来谈谈卢克的事的
Well, today I'm here to talk about Luke.
是做实验用的小兔子吗
Is that the science rabbit?
是我儿子
That's my son.
当然啦
Yes. Of course.
我想说的就是跟这个有关的
That's sort of the point.
我觉得他感觉有点被忽视了
I think he's feeling a little bit overlooked.
我想知道你能不能
I was wondering if you could just,
今天颁给他一个奖项
you know, toss him one of those awards today.
就...
Just...
恐怕所有的获奖者
Well, I'm afraid all of the award winners
都已经决定了
have already been decided.
不过 如果这能让他感觉更好的话
Oh, but, hey, if it makes him feel better,
他之前在竞争品格正直奖
he was in the running for the integrity award.
他只是被对手打败了
He just got edged out by --
斯科特·威勒吗
Scott Wheeler?
那小子简直是个缉毒特警
Oh, that little weasel's a narc.
2008年万圣节嘉年华
Halloween carnival, 2008 --
"邓菲太太的葡萄汁闻起来有药味"
"Mrs. Dunphy's grape juice smells like medicine."
那个上午好漫长
It was a long morning.
这对他来说会意义重大的
It would mean so much to him.
克莱尔
Well, Claire...
那不公平
That wouldn't be fair.
我不知道 对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我真的好令人感到难堪
I-I-I really am -- so embarrassing.
也许我能
Maybe there's some sort of, um --
我说不好 捐一笔钱
I don't know, like, a -- a -- a donation or something
给汽车店 来给车轮上上油 促成事儿
I could give to the auto shop to, um...grease the wheels.
我们不缺油
We're good on grease.
但是有多少制动液都不嫌多[打住]
But you can never have too much brake fluid, so --
也许足球队需要一些防滑钉
Or perhaps the soccer team could use some new cleats,
-帮他们 -反击吗[回扣]
- help them get their... - Kick back?
好了 邓菲太太 我真的在尽量
Okay, Mrs. Dunphy, I'm really doing everything I can
无视你想贿赂我 从而让你儿子获得
to ignore the fact that you're trying to bribe me
马龙·邦尼菲斯品格正直奖这一事实
for the Marlon Boniface integrity award.
很高兴你能记得那个名字
I'm so glad you can remember that name,
但你连卢克都记不住
but you can't remember Luke.
我这个月第一次放假
My first day off in a month,
我要出去跟歌洛莉亚逛街
I'm headed out the door to go shopping with Gloria,
结果我的蠢老板需要我去拿兰花
and my stupid boss needs me to pick up some stupid orchid.
好像我的时间就不值钱一样
Like my time's not valuable?
歌洛莉亚要帮我选足环呢
Gloria was gonna help me pick out a toe ring.
我不管你是不是非法的[偷渡民]
Oh, I don't care if you are here illegally,
你太美了
you're gorgeous.
听着先生 告诉你一下 我...
Listen, mister, for your information, I am --
花 他说的是花
Flower. He's talking...flower.
加文 我想给你介绍...
Gavin, I would like to introduce you --
我要的米兰秀的照片呢
Where are the photos from the Milan Show I asked for?
我不记得你要过啊
I-I don't remember you asking for them.
我想我俩之间有人搞错了 但是是谁呢
Oh. I guess one of us is mistaken, but who?
因为引领了袜子新长度
The fashion icon profiled by Vanity Fair
而登上《名利场》的时尚偶像
for pioneering a new sock length,
还是共用订书机的兼职员工
or the part-time employee who shares a stapler?
对不起
Sorry.
对不起 对不起 给你
Sorry, sorry, sorry. Here they are.
瞧瞧秋季的新品
Oh, look what's new for fall.
拇指纹
Thumbprints.
你知道泰国 德国 阿根廷 墨西哥的
Do you know the Thai, German, Argentine, Mexican
-美食车"返璞归真"吗 -知道
- gourmet food truck back to basics? - Yes.
我需要你帮我站位预定
I need you to make me a standing reservation there.
我要怎么站位预定啊
How do I make a standing reservation?
那里很难停车
Parking's a bitch.
我需要你过去 找个地方
I need you to go there, find a spot,
站在那里直到我过去
and stand in it until I arrive.
我想杀了他
I wanted to kill him.
但我保持沉默了 因为这家人
But I bite my tongue, because in this family,
觉得我是哥伦比亚的急性子[热头]
they think that I am a Colombian hothead,
这很疯狂 因为哥伦比亚的急性子
which is crazy because a colombian hot head is
会烧了别人的头
when you set somebody's head on fire.
气味很臭 但能让别人记住教训
It smells terrible, but it sends a message.
去别的地方停车
Go somewhere else.
是我 歌洛莉亚
It's me -- Gloria.
你干什么呢 我跟你说了自己去逛街
What are you doing? I told you to go shopping without me.
我知道你站在这里像是橙色交通锥一样
I couldn't enjoy it knowing you're standing there
就没法享受逛街了
like a little orange cone.
这是我的工作 没事的
It's my job. It's fine.
不 这是不对的 他是个糟糕的人
No, it's not fine. He's a terrible man.
但我做了点事 让你感觉好些
But I did a little something to make you feel better.
天啊 你做了什么
Oh, my god, what have you done?
他敢整我爱的人
He messes with something I love --
我就去破坏他喜欢的东西
I mess with something he loves.
这东西一丢
The second it goes missing,
他就会去查监控
he's going to check security cameras,
然后我就会被炒鱿鱼
and I'm going to get fired.
那又怎样
So what?
他是我见过最差劲的人
He's the worst person I have ever met,
我当年住的村子里可有个人
and there was a man in my village
叫"揍孩暴徒弗拉维奥"
named Flavio the Baby Puncher.
喂 占车位的 动一动
Hey, cone. Move.
好吧 我就走
Okay. Um, just -- just leaving.
喂
Hello?
快一点
Faster.
我试图贿赂校长已经被发现了
I'd already been caught trying to bribe the principal,
可不管你信不信
but believe it or not,
我还在想办法
I was still trying to think of a way
帮卢克拿到那个奖
to get Luke that award.
然后我看到了斯科特·威勒
Then I saw Scott Wheeler.
没错 他是个小缉毒警 也是个老好人
Yeah, he was a narc and a goody two-shoes,
但他毕竟还是个孩子
but he was also just a child.
然后我就知道该做什么了
And I knew the right thing to do.
有时候你只需要轻轻"推"一下
Sometimes all it takes is a little nudge.
怎么了
What?
-他太可爱了 -就是啊
- He is so adorable. - I know, isn't he?
还记得莉莉像他这么大的时候吗
Remember when Lily was like this?
背着我说什么呢
What do you say when I'm not here?
乔 给米奇尔看看
Joe, let's show Mitchell
你怎么接球扔球的
how you can catch and throw the ball.
来看看
Let's see.
这是在教我吗
Is this so that I'll learn?
对啊 不 不是 不过
Oh, yes -- well, no, but, I mean,
要是你能学会就太好了
if you pick up on it, that'd be great.
好吧 这样
Well, no, actually, here --
乔 我们来给小卡展示一下怎么跳舞
Joe, let's show Cam how we can dance, huh?
我喜欢舞会
I love a dance party.
就是这样 我喜欢这个节奏
Oh, there we are. I like this beat.
-我要一起吗 -当然
- Should I join you? - Yes, of course.
盛情难却啊
Okay, if you insist.
多好玩啊
Oh, how fun is this?
太好玩了
So fun.
-你看起来很开心 -你看起来也很开心
- You look so happy. - You look so happy.
不 说真的 我真希望你能看到
No, seriously, I wish you could see
自己这么开心的样子
the happy look on your face.
如果那有你一半开心的话
Well, if it's half as happy as the look on your face...
米奇尔 你心里想的
Mitchell, are we almost discussing
是不是跟我想的是一样的
what I think we're almost discussing?
-我想再要一个孩子 -我也是
- I want to have another baby. - I do, too.
我只是不敢说出口
I just was afraid to say anything.
我也是
I was, too.
可现在似乎是个好机会
I -- but the timing seems right, right?
我们的想法都差不多
I mean, we both seem to be on the same page.
我好怀念家里有个小宝宝的日子
I-I just really miss having a baby around.
小孩子在墙上的涂鸦
The writing's on the wall.
可主要是在窗帘上
But mostly on the curtains.
天啊 好吧
Oh, boy, okay.
没关系
Oh. All right. That's fine.
要喝水的话椅子下面有
There's water underneath the seat there if you want it.
上货区的那些人
Those guys at the loading dock
看到我拖的是公主城堡
really gave me the business
一直在笑话我
when they found out I was hauling a princess castle.
他在为什么事烦恼 我要跟他谈一下
Something was bugging him. He needed to talk.
我真是自讨苦吃啊
It's like I don't want to be happy.
很明显你有心事
Well, you've obviously got something on your mind.
克莱尔和我闹了点不愉快
Claire and I had a thing.
你知道了肯定要笑话我的
Oh, you're just gonna make fun of me.
不会的 我保证不笑话你
No, I promise I won't make fun of you.
我一直想要一台吃豆女士游戏机
I've always wanted a "Ms. Pac-man" machine,
可是克莱尔说不行
but Claire said no.
其实她什么都没说
Actually, she didn't say anything.
她只是发出不同意的声音 我就放弃了
She just made a disapproving noise, and I rolled over.
我很懦弱吧
Pretty wimpy, huh?
不 我也经历过
No. I've been there.
-真的吗 -有些时候没办法
- Really? - You have to sometimes.
婚姻就是这样
That's the way marriages work.
老婆高兴你才能有好日子什么的
All this happy wife, happy life sort of stuff.
我告诉你什么会让我高兴
Tell you what would make me happy.
就是这个小家伙
This bad boy right here.
还在我的购物车里呢
It's still in my shopping cart
因为我没法放弃
Cause I just can't say goodbye.
谁不想要幸福生活
Who doesn't want a happy life?
不过很快你就会想都不想地说
But soon you're saying, "Yes, dear,"
"是 亲爱的
and, "whatever you need, dear,"
你说什么就是什么 亲爱的"
without even thinking about it.
防反光有机玻璃 舞台效果增强
Anti-glare plexi, reinforced podium.
偶尔就站起来跟你对着干 你一点办法都没有
Stand up every once in a while, you lose all your power.
甚至还有专门放手的手腕垫
It's even got a wrist pad for your knob hand.
没等你反应过来
Before you know it,
就已经载着一座粉色的公主城堡
you're picking up a pink princess castle
给做了美甲的两岁小孩送去
for your pedicured 2-year-old,
完全丧失了最后一个
saying goodbye to your last chance
培养铁血真汉子的机会
to have one red-blooded man in the family.
把游戏买下来吧 菲尔
And you're getting that damn game, Phil!
看在吃豆人之父岩谷彻的份上
What in the name of "Pac-man" creator toru iwatani
-你都做了什么 -你值得这个
- have you done?! - You deserve it.
你努力工作 养家糊口
You work hard. You provide for your family.
不能有遗憾
No regrets.
你知道吗 我一点都不后悔
You know what? I don't regret it.
你当然不
Of course you don't.
我是吃豆女士的主人
I'm the owner of a "Ms. Pac-man"!
真是太爽了
This is exhilarating!
谢谢你 杰
Thanks, Jay.
话说 时不时的
You know, every now and then,
-我会想知道你对我的真正看法 -就此打住
- I wonder how you really feel about me. - Bup bup!
我知道你也会为我这么做的
I'm sure you'd do the same for me.
-懂了 -那就好
- Gotcha. - Good.
-明白你的意思了 -很好
- Message received. - Good.
你都干了什么
What the hell did you do?!
你不是给我了点暗示吗
I thought you sent me a message!
你疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?!
谢天谢地 城堡还是好的
Thank God it's still in one piece.
也许我们可以
We can probably--
好了 傻蛋
Okay, dummy.
我们把这东西挪到后院
We get this thing in the backyard,
自己拼起来
we nail it together,
歌洛莉亚永远也不会发现
and Gloria will never find out.
别这么做 杰
Don't do this, Jay.
作为你最好的朋友 我恳求你
As your best friend, I implore you.
如果我们重建城堡的话
If we rebuild this castle,
我们就摧毁了今天所建造的一切
we tear down everything we built today.
你在说什么
What? And what?!
我们今天站起来了反抗
We stood up for ourselves.
已经没有回头路了
There's no turning back.
我们要向克莱尔和歌洛莉亚坦白我们的所为
We're going to tell Claire and Gloria what we did.
我怕了 菲尔 可以吗
I'm scared, Phil, okay?
她们要的就是这种害怕 那只会让她们更嚣张
They count on that fear. They feed off it.
不能再这样了
No more.
某人看上去大汗淋漓 甚是性感啊
Someone's looking sexy and sweaty.
没错
That's right.
那个性感猛男
And this sexy, sweaty someone
现在成了吃豆女士的主人
is now the proud owner of a vintage "Ms. Pac-man" game.
游戏机送到了吗
Oh, it came?
那些人说好明天才送的
They promised they weren't gonna deliver it until tomorrow.
我还想看看你惊喜的表情呢
I wanted to be there to see your face.
今早你说你想自己买一个的时候
It was killing me this morning
我差点就忍不住告诉你了
when you said you wanted to get your own.
你喜欢吗
Do ya love it?
喜欢 我爱你
Love, I love you.
杰
Jay?
你怎么花了这么久
What took you so long?
乔30分钟后就要回来了
Joe's gonna be here in 30 minutes.
城堡怎么了
What happened to the castle?
出了点小差错
Little snafu.
说到这个公主城堡
About this princess castle--
那是什么
What's that?
黑油漆还有海盗旗
Black paint and a skull flag
这样我们就能把公主城堡
so that we can turn this princess thing
弄成海盗城堡了
into a pirate castle.
海盗城堡吗
Pirate castle?
对啊 他毕竟是个男孩子
Yes. He's a boy.
我们不是谈过了吗
We have talked about this.
男人为什么总听不进去呢
Why do men never listen?
就知道嘴上说着 "没问题亲爱的"
It's always, "Sure, honey. Sure, honey."
谁知道呢 婚姻总是这么不易
I don't know. Marriage is hard.
好了 现在问题都可以解决
Okay, we can solve both our problems.
把这个公主城堡在30分钟内拼好
We put this princess castle together in the next 30 minutes.
-走吧 -这怎么能解决我的问题
- Let's go! - How does that solve my problem?
快行动
Just go!
天啊 发生了什么
Oh, my gosh, what happened?
乔把莉莉的车开出来玩了一下
Joe took Lily's car for a little spin.
发生了一点小事故 不过没事
Had a little fern-der bender, but it's okay. It's fine.
他刚刚画过的窗帘
Well, the curtains he drew on
要送去专业清洁店才行
are gonna need to be professionally cleaned,
不过窗帘早就该送去洗了
But they were overdue.
是啊 重回这种干劲十足的状态真好
Yeah. It's fun having this energy back in the house.
是啊 那个刚刚吃饱了布丁的小家伙呢
It is. Where is that little pudding-filled rocket, anyway?
他在这里
Oh, there he is. There he goes.
-你看见他了 -他要去卫生间了
- You see him? - Okay, yeah, he's going into the bathroom.
-他把门锁上了 -锁上了
- Okay. Oh. It's locked. - Locked?
我们去开另外一扇门
I'm gonna go around to the other door. Yeah.
-乔 -乔
- Joe! - Joe!
马桶肯定堵上了
Okay, well, that's gonna clog.
好吧 我来拿马桶塞
All right, I'll get the plunger.
亲爱的 听好了
Okay, now, sweetie, listen.
我们不能用这么多厕纸
We can't use that much toilet paper
因为这样很浪费
because it's wasteful.
不好 我的钥匙
Oh, my gosh. My keys.
不 不 不 不要
No, no! No! No, no, no!
真好 没堵住啊
Oh, good, it didn't clog.
天呐
Okay. Oh, geez.
莉莉 是你把紫色颜料洒在地上的吗
Lily, did you spill purple paint on the floor?
是啊 今天的麻烦精是我呢
Yeah, I'm the problem today.
天呐
Oh, geez.
天啊 范德考夫沙发被毁了
Oh, God! The vanderkolff!
什么
What?
天呐 沙发
Oh, God, the vanderkoff!
没事 没关系
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
把它送去专业清洁店就好了
We'll, we'll just get it professionally cleaned.
是啊 跟窗帘一起送去
Yeah, w-we'll just throw it in with the curtains.
球球
Ball!
不 那不是球球
Oh, no, that's not a ball.
不不不 那是个贵到吓死人的圣安杰洛牌玻璃碗
No. No, no, no. That's a criminally expensive Santangelo bowl.
听着 我悄悄地绕到后面去
Okay, I'm gonna sneak around behind him
你继续说话分散他的注意力
snd you're just gonna keep him talking.
乔 你不想这么做的
Joe, you don't want to do this.
现在你还没有犯下大错
You know, as of right now, you haven't done anything wrong.
把碗给我
You just hand that over to me,
大家相安无事 好吗
and it's like nothing ever happened, see?
他又不是长着婴儿脸的罪犯 他就是个小孩而已
Okay, he's not baby face nelson. He's an actual baby.
你想来帮忙吗
Okay, you know what? You want to help out?
扔点东西过来垫着 比如靠枕
Slide something underneath it like a throw pillow.
扔球球
Throw!
我们都忘了小孩子有多麻烦 对吧
You forget what a handful kids are when they're little, huh?
是啊 我之前都没意识到 现在莉莉这么大了
Yeah, I didn't realize how easy we have it
-我们过得有多舒坦 -是啊
- Now that Lily's so independent. - Yeah.
再说 我们也不像莉莉当年这么大时那样年轻了
Plus, we're not as young as we were when she was like this.
米奇 我们是不是在讨论
Mitchell, are -- are we almost discussing
我脑海中想的那件事
What I think we're almost discussing?
也许我们不该急着领养孩子
Maybe we shouldn't rush into having another kid?
这是大事 而且我喜欢现在的生活状态
It's a big decision, and I love the way our lives are now.
天呐 我也是
Oh, god, me, too!
这不代表我们是自私的人吧
Th-th-this doesn't make us selfish people, does it?
当然不是了
Of course not.
小乔卡在井里了["好"字]
Baby Joe's stuck in the well.
-管他的呢 -能有啥事
- Leave him. - He‘s fine.
不对 往左边放点
No, no, no. A little bit more to the left.
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
不敢相信我得求你去购物
I can't believe I have to beg you to go shopping.
我得确保
Well, I have to make sure
你把这东西放对地方
that you're putting that thing in the right place
因为你觉得这份蠢工作对你很重要
since this stupid, horrible job is so important to you.
海莉啊 我得说
Ay, Haley, I have to say,
今天让我有点瞧不起你
today I lost a little bit of respect for you.
不送 歌洛莉亚
Goodbye, Gloria.
你得学会站起来维护自己
You need to learn how to stand up for yourself.
你知道你说出这话有多容易吧
Do you know how easy that is for you to say?
才怪 说英语对我来说很难的
No, no. Nothing in English is easy for me to say.
跟你不同 我没有有钱的老公
Unlike you, I don't have a rich husband.
大家都觉得我什么事都会搞砸
What I do have is a reputation for being a screw-up
什么事都坚持不下去
who never follows through on anything.
这就是为什么 如果你没留意到的话
which is why, in case you haven't noticed,
两年的大学我已经读了第三年了
I'm in my third year of a two-year college program
而且还住在父母的地下室里
and still living in my parents' basement.
听着 我知道这份工作很挫
Look, I know that this job sucks,
但也许能让我有所成就
but it might actually lead to something.
你知道5年前谁在干这份工作吗
Do you know who had this job five years ago?
加文 而且他老板比他还混蛋
Gavin, and he worked for an even bigger jackass than he is.
你好啊 午餐吃得可真快啊
Hey! That was a quick lunch.
是啊 队排得太短了
Yeah, the line was too short.
他家没戏了 我不能被看见去那里进餐
It's over. I can't be seen there.
我可不想让人觉得我是混蛋
I wouldn't want people to think I was a jackass.
听着 我刚刚那么说
Uh, look, when -- when I said that,
真的不是...
I really didn't --
首先 你刚刚都打算离开了
Okay, first of all, you were just leaving.
第二 永远别回来了
Second of all, maybe permanently.
滚快点
Faster.
你知道吗 加文
You know what, Gavin?
-我受够了 -别
- I have had enough of -- - No.
搞什么 为什么不行
What? Why not?
是时候站起来跟他翻脸了
It's time I stood up to this guy.
我可能会被抄
I'm probably gonna get fired,
不如趁还有牙医保险 痛痛快快翻脸
so I might as well get in a couple shots before I lose my dental.
不 你刚刚说得没错
No, you were right before.
像我这样很容易
It's very easy to be like me,
不用脑子去想 先吼完再说
to scream first and think later.
但世界不是这个样子的
But that's not how the world works.
我去跟他谈谈
Let me go talk to him.
-不要 -要
- No. - Yes.
这一切都是我造成的
I caused all this.
不管怎样 时不时
Anyways, it's good for me every once in a while
委屈一下自己挺好的
to swallow my pride.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
就想让你听听老娘的声音
I just want you to listen to my voice
看着老娘的眼睛 仔细想想
and look into my eyes and ask yourself,
这个尤物一路从哥伦比亚闯到美国
"Did this woman made it all the way here from colombia
难道不认识一些狠角儿吗
without knowing some very bad men
他们会不会帮她的忙呢
who would love to do her a favor?"
我不知道接下来会发生什么
Okay. I don't know what's gonna happen next,
但道歉的感觉真好
but it feels so good to apologize.
天呐 我保住工作了
Oh, my god, I still have my job.
真棒 我们去庆祝吧
Oh, that's great! Let's go celebrate.
可惜 我去不了
Oh, you know what? I can't.
我得去他家前院的草坪上撒种子
I have to go spread seeds on his front lawn
那样他回家时 可以享受从鸟群经过的感觉
so he can run through birds when he gets home.
我还得再去道个歉
I have one more thing that I need to apologize for.
叫我元素周期表 因为我全身都是"金属"[奖牌]
Call me the periodic table, 'cause I got all the "Metals."
不错啊 宝贝
That's nice, honey.
卢克 你今天过得怎么样
Luke, how was your day?
卢克拿到了邦尼菲斯品格正直奖
Well, Luke won the Boniface integrity award,
我可是拿到了
whereas I got all --
没搞错吧
Are you kidding me?
那真是太棒了
That is fantastic!
我为你骄傲...
I'm so proud of --
怂人
The bonerface!
得这个奖的人 大家都叫他怂人
You win that award, everyone calls you "Bonerface."
这是书呆子奖里的巅峰
It's the super nerd award.
一个女同学把我的内裤拉到头上
My underwear got pulled over my head by a girl.
一直都是斯科特·威勒得这奖的
It always goes to Scott Wheeler,
但有人把他的车停到残疾人专用位上了
But someone pushed his car into a handicapped spot
然后我就拿到了这奖
So I'd get the award.
我知道这事是谁干的
And I think I know exactly who did it.
-这个嘛 -就是曼尼
- Well -- - Manny!
你陷害斯科特·威勒 所以我变成了怂人
You framed Scott Wheeler so I'd win the bonerface.
这得通哦
It adds up.
首先声音小点 你又不是装卸工
First, lower your voice. We're not stevedores.
第二你错了
Second, you're wrong.
第三 反正你活该
Third, it serves you right, anyway,
谁让你勾搭莎拉·芬克的
after you hit on Sarah Fink.
得了吧
Oh, for god's sake.
天涯何处无妹子
There are plenty of other girls out there.
忘了她吧
Get over it.
那是斯里兰卡的肉桂棒
That cinnamon stick is from SriLlanka!
放开我
Get off me!
你身上一股香薰蜡烛味儿
You smell like a candle.
这是薰衣草味沐浴珠的味道 你这混蛋
It's lavender bath beads, you son of a bitch!
那么荣获"最无谓撕逼"奖的是...
And the award for the saddest brawl goes to
够了 住手 给我住手
Okay, stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
是我做的 是我让你成了怂人
I did it! I did it! I got you the Bonerface!
那个邦尼什么奖 叫什么来着
Ugh the Bonifa-- what's it called?
都走开吧
Just get out of here.
-你干的 -是我
- You? - Yes.
为什么
Why?
因为我不知道这是个给书呆子的奖
Because I didn't know it was a nerd award.
我知道它是个奖 我想让你得一次
I just knew it was an award, and I wanted you to have one.
然后你刚好排第二 好吧
And you were second in line to get it, anyway,
所以我就 你懂的
so I just, you know...
暗中耍手段 因为你觉得我是个废柴
Rigged it because you think I'm a loser
靠自己的力量永远都赢不了一个奖
who could never win his own award?
不 不是的
No. No.
我 我只是
I-I just...
因为艾丽克斯得了那么多奖...
Alex has her awards and
谢谢你对我这么有信心啊
Thanks for believing in me.
乔马上就要过来了
Joe's gonna be here soon.
我们得快点 窗已经弄好了
Let's pick up the pace. Window looks good.
把屋顶盖上去
Let's raise the roof.
杰 我觉得还没到完工庆祝的时候
I don't think it's time to celebrate, Jay.
我们都还没盖屋 噢
We haven't even put on the roo-- oh.
宝贝
Honey.
真的对不起
I am so sorry.
你早上看上去那么沮丧
You just seemed so upset this morning,
我就以为这是因为得奖日还有艾丽克斯
and I assumed it was about awards day and Alex.
我根本不在乎得没得奖
I don't even care about awards.
那你为什么不愿意去上学
Then why didn't you want to go to school?
该不会是因为
This isn't still about that fight
你跟曼尼在抢萨拉·芬克吧 是吗
that you're having with Manny over Sarah Fink, is it?
我根本就不喜欢萨拉·芬克
I don't even like Sarah Fink.
我都已经叫她不要再打电话给我了
I told her to stop calling me.
好吧 那为什么曼尼还以为你
Well, then why does Manny think that you're...
你没有勾搭她 是她勾搭你的
You didn't hit on her. She hit on you.
所以你 你是在努力不让曼尼伤心
And you're -- you're trying to spare Manny's feelings.
我真是世界上最笨的笨蛋
I am the dumbest person in the world
居然以为你会需要我的帮助
to think that you would ever need my help
才能获得品格正直奖
to win an integrity award.
我真是太为你骄傲了
I could not be prouder.
明年再说吧 艾丽克斯
Maybe next year, Alex.
搞定 遮阳蓬都装好了
Okay. Awning is done.
那本来应该是个吊桥的
Supposed to be a drawbridge.
难道那些链条都没让你反应过来吗
Weren't the chains a clue?
你还有脸喷我
A lot of criticism
你刚刚才把自己的鞋子锯掉了一半
from a guy who just sawe1d half his shoe off.
开什么玩笑呢
Who are we kidding?
我们把门装倒了
We got a wall on backwards.
我连那些东西该怎么装都不知道
I don't even know where that stuff goes.
看上去都不怎么像...
It barely looks like a --
城堡
Castle!
乔 慢点
Joe, wait!
嘿 小家伙
Hey, buddy.
嘿 这要是涂好漆了看上去会更漂亮
Hey, it's gonna look even better when it's painted.
那遮阳蓬感觉不错
Ah, the awning's a nice touch.
杰 这个城堡本来应该更...
Jay, this castle's supposed to look like so --
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness!
乔 看看你做的好事
Oh, Joe, look what you did.
你觉得我会相信
Do you expect me to believe
一个两岁的小宝宝能瞬间摧毁一座城堡吗
that a 2-year-old can destroy a whole house in one second?
-可以的 -淡定
- Oh, wow, yes. - Easy.
绝对可以
For sure.
杰 你要不要告诉我到底发生了什么
Jay, do you want to tell me what really happened?
一个人如果要成事
No one wins anything
就需要家人和朋友的帮助
without help from family and friends
指引你丢掉错的想法
who steer you away from bad ideas...
慢着 菲尔 菲尔
Wait, Phil! Phil! Phil!
并作出对的选择
...and toward good ones.
我不知道我们今天这是怎么了
I don't know what got into us today.
你说关于宝宝的事情吗
Oh, with the baby thing?
是的 我现在最不需要的就是个熊孩子了
Yes. It's the last thing I need right now.
-我们都不需要了 -对
- It's the last thing any of us need right now. - Yeah.
因为每个人的成功
Because every time anyone accomplishes anything...
-背后都有 -做得不错嘛
- he or she achieves it... - Nice.
无数个沉默的英雄
...with the help of a thousand silent heroes.
无私的伙伴伸出他们的援手
the selfless team players who offer their support,
并不是为了被认可
not to be recognized,
而是因为那是对的事
but because it's the right thing to do.
人们并不经常会因为
Awards aren't usually given out
是个好人而被嘉奖 但是今天
being a good person, but today...
他们会被嘉奖
they are.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen, the winner
获得"马龙·邦尼菲斯"品格正直奖的是
of the Marlon Boniface integrity award is...
真是太棒了
This is awesome.
-卢克·邓菲 -不要啊
- Luke Dunphy. - No!
艾丽克斯·邓菲
Alex Dunphy.
哇 这真是个惊喜
Wow, this is a surprise.
让我来讲一个关于追梦小女孩的故事
Let me tell you about a little girl with a dream.
非常 非常感谢
Muchas, muchas gracias.
我刚才说到哪儿了
Where was I?
颁奖日啊
Awards day...
或者像桑杰·帕特尔认为的 是逾越节
or as Sanjay Patel knows it, passover.
那个小女孩想要的
All that little girl wanted
不过是台计算器和一个机会
was a calculator and a chance.